Eric Um

 \bigsqcup LinkedIn | \square 615-580-9641 | \square umeric@yahoo.com | \square Github

Career Summary

Salesforce professional with 3 years of healthcare and IT experience at Acadia Healthcare, a national leader in behavioral healthcare. My engagement with Salesforce has cultivated a keen interest in data. Eager to advance my skills in the direction of data and contribute positively as I continue to evolve.

Technical Skills

Data Engineering | ETL/ELT, API Integration, Data Analysis

Programming | Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Database Management | PostgreSQL, pgAdmin4, Azure SQL Database

Cloud Platforms | Microsoft Azure, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure Data Factory

Work Experience

Salesforce Application Analyst Acadia Healthcare - Franklin, TN | 05/2021 - Current

- Implemented data flow to optimize provisioning of inactive users, reducing admin support by 20%.
- Formulated a comprehensive Excel-based user setup system to ensure accurate onboarding of intake and business users when granting appropriate access to the applications.
- Provided data support to over 1000 users in the areas of Business Development and Admissions/Intake, enhancing user engagement in Salesforce.
- Collaborate on test scripts with development and configuration teams using Azure DevOps. Ensure comprehensive testing of new features, enhancements, and changes in application.

Service Desk Analyst Acadia Healthcare - Nashville, TN | 09/2020 - 05/2021

- Developed comprehensive training documentation and guides for the onboarding process, ensuring the successful preparation and development of new employees.
- Addressed and resolved more than 1000 tickets, offering detailed information and effective solutions to various user issues.

Maintenance Assistant/Assembler Johnson Controls - Murfreesboro, TN | 03/2014 – 07/2016

- Developed mitigation strategies to meet OSHA standards, ensuring a safe work environment.
- Designed innovative tools to increase production efficiency and employee safety.

Education & Certifications

Motlow Community College | Associate of Information Technology Major Cyber Security

DP - 900 | Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals

DP - 203 | Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate

Technical Projects

1. ETL Anxiety & Depression Symptoms Data

Use ETL process on depression data to explore race-related differences in anxiety and depression symptoms to analyze trends over the years related, and identify regions with a higher prevalence of symptoms.

Resources Used:

- CDC API: Gathered authoritative data on anxiety and depression symptoms.
- Visual Studio with Python: Leveraged for efficient data extraction, transformation, and loading.
- PostgreSQL: Chosen as the reliable data storage solution.
- pgAdmin4: Utilized for seamless data querying and management.
- Flourish: Applied to create engaging visual graphs for data representation.

2. Google API Integration for Houston Restaurants

Integrating Google API to retrieve data on Houston restaurants. Utilizing Azure data tools to move the API data to Azure Data Warehouse, gaining insights into top-rated restaurants, focusing on highly rated and budget-friendly options.

Resources Used:

- Google Places API: Obtained comprehensive data on Houston restaurants.
- Visual Studio: Applied for effective data extraction and preparation for database storage.
- Azure Pipelines: Facilitated data transformation and loading into the data lake.
- Azure Synapse Studio: Utilized for creating SQL scripts to refine and analyze data.
- Flourish: Employed to create a visual chart for clear data representation.

3. Web Portfolio with Data Engineering Projects

Web portfolio showcasing various data engineering projects. Highlighting front-end skills while presenting data-driven projects. https://umericdev.z19.web.core.windows.net/

Resources Used:

- Visual Studio: Employed to create a front-end website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Azure Storage Account: Utilized for data management and hosting of the static website.
- Azure Static Website: Used to deploy and serve the static web content.